<annotation>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00003CXA6:6th_sc:john_s._graham
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00003CXA6
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Gettysburg (Widescreen Edition): DVD: Tom Berenger,Martin Sheen
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            6th SC
        </title>
        <date>
            November 9, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            John S. Graham
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Gadsden, AL United States
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Great visual of the battle where my great grandfather fought with the 6th SC.  Entertaining and educational
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00003CXA6:no_doubt_it's_great:j._greller
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00003CXA6
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Gettysburg (Widescreen Edition): DVD: Tom Berenger,Martin Sheen
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            No Doubt It's Great
        </title>
        <date>
            October 19, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            J. Greller
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            san francisco
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            There is no questioning this film is done very well. That said, it should be pointed out that it may not be for everyone. If you are not a fan of cliches, stay away from this. There are TONS of monologues that go on for long periods of time with epic music in the background, and maybe not everyone can handle that. Most of the performances are incredible, my favorite happens to be Jeff Daniels. One performance that doesn't do it for me is Martin Sheen. He shares a lot of scenes with Tom Berenger and it seems like Berenger is the one keeping those scenes afloat. C. Thomas Howell has a steady part but you won't recognize him as the kid from the Outsiders. Great battle scenes, especially the big one in the open field at the end.
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00003CXA6:we_do_what_we_must_do.:david_a._baer
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00003CXA6
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Gettysburg (Widescreen Edition): DVD: Tom Berenger,Martin Sheen
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 1
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            We do what we must do.
        </title>
        <date>
            September 26, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            David A. Baer
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Indianapolis, IN  USA
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            After the heart-rending nobility of Abraham Lincoln's verbal tribute to Gettysburg's fallen, there is not much else that could do those men justice.
            Yet GETTYSBURG does so.
            This 1993 film, second in a civil war trilogy that begins with GODS AND GENERALS and concludes with LAST FULL MEASURE is worlds beyond its predecessor in cinematographic and dramatic prowess. To put it as succinctly as possible, this is a profoundly moving four hours of personalized history.
            A film like this helps us to recall that we are not yet one hundred fifty years from southeastern Pennyslvania's momentary appearance as a killing field. In America's most costly war, this was its linchpin battle.
            Tom Berenger and Martin Sheen turn in understated and powerful renderings of Confederate generals. Sheen's Robert E. Lee carries a mountain's weight of burden on his grieving shoulders even as he makes the decisions that will send still more Virginia gentlemen and Texas cowboys to their deaths. Jeff Daniels far outshines his earlier representation of Maine's Coronel Chamberlain, the six-times wounded college professor who would finish his working life as the president of Bowdoin College.
            The panoramic battle scenes provided legions of Civil War reenactors with their glorious opportunity, one that - with the exception of a handful of volunteers who couldn't help grinning while they were being shot down - seized the day with remarkable poignance.
            This one is for seeing again and again, remembering, and bowing one's head against the awful fact that nations are too often born in blood
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00003CXA6:this_is_a_great_movie!:carla_june_bishop
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00003CXA6
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Gettysburg (Widescreen Edition): DVD: Tom Berenger,Martin Sheen
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            This is a great movie!
        </title>
        <date>
            September 7, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Carla June Bishop
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Carbondale, Illinois
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            If you're into the Civil War, this is the movie for you.  It tells the battle from both sides.  It follows the activities of both sides.   This is a must have for fans of the Civil War
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00003CXA6:i_wish_i_was_in_dixie...:eric_"trampster"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00003CXA6
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Gettysburg (Widescreen Edition): DVD: Tom Berenger,Martin Sheen
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 1
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            I wish I was in Dixie...
        </title>
        <date>
            August 19, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Eric "Trampster"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            France
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            This is one of the best movie about the civil war I've ever seen. It is the most instructive, realistic, with very good actors playing in it ! For once, just like in "Gods and Generals", the movie is more focused on the southern side, which is not very often the case.
            I am a fan of this part of the U.S. history, and especially of the South, and I was really captivated by this movie from the beginning to the end
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00003CXA6:civil_war_magnitude:frank_h._crisman_"frank_crisman"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00003CXA6
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Gettysburg (Widescreen Edition): DVD: Tom Berenger,Martin Sheen
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 2
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Civil War Magnitude
        </title>
        <date>
            August 18, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Frank H. Crisman "Frank Crisman"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Michigan
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Almost a complete scope of the battle of the size of the battle in numbers and cause. Would have like to have heard Lincoln's
            Address at the end for now it is a rememberance of the dead of
            both sides of the battle that, I think, unitesw  us now into
            this great nation
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00003CXA6:an_outstanding_movie:kyle_pratt
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00003CXA6
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Gettysburg (Widescreen Edition): DVD: Tom Berenger,Martin Sheen
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            3 of 3
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            An Outstanding Movie
        </title>
        <date>
            August 16, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Kyle Pratt
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Chehalis, WA, USA
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            This 1993 movie, based on Michael Shaara's book The Killer Angels, is over four hours long, but it uses that time well to document this critical Civil War battle.  I used the word `document' on purpose because this movie is accurate to the point of being a documentary.  It was even filmed at the Gettysburg National Military Park.  When you see the fight for Little Round Top or Pickett's Charge, or another fight, you are seeing the events much as they happened where they happened.
            Thousands of civil war re-enactors play the everyday soldiers you see in the background and in the grand charges of this battle.  These amateur enthusiasts put their heart into this movie and it shows.
            As a high school history teacher, I was timing certain parts of the movie to show in class.  When I timed Pickett's Charge, I realized it is shown in real time.  Those Confederate soldiers charged into Union gunfire for 28 minutes and you see every moment in this movie.
            Read The Killer Angels and then see this outstanding movie.
            Kyle Prat
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00003CXA6:flawed,_but_effective:straitjacket_fits_"straitjacket_fits"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00003CXA6
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Gettysburg (Widescreen Edition): DVD: Tom Berenger,Martin Sheen
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            4 of 9
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Flawed, but effective
        </title>
        <date>
            July 20, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Straitjacket Fits "Straitjacket Fits"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Durham, NC
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Despite the chintzy, unconvincing facial hair (Jeff Daniels' being the exception); Martin Sheen's too-gentlemanly interpretation of Gen. Lee's accent (and his beard); obvious &amp; saccharine soliloquies about the higher purpose for fighting the war; generalized (and largely inaccurate) interpretations of the underlying history of the war; and hopelessly, ridiculously, wildly off-the-mark attempts atNew England accents, the film still works.
            I understand that to get a film produced and distributed, it is often necessary to have recognizable names in the cast.  But an unknown who looks more like General Lee than Martin Sheen would have been a better choice.  And C. Thomas Howell's performance--well, let's just say that his glued-on beard was more convincing than his acting.  Jeff Daniels, however, does an excellent job, in large part because he doesn't try to convince you he's from New England and consequently does not come off like Cliff from Cheers, using every stereotype associated with nasal 'r'-dropping.  Instead of focusing on the so-called nasality of  the NE accent (think of Sheen in The Missiles of Octobah), Daniels allows the viewer to suspend disbelief.  But then, here comes CT Howell again to slap you across the face and remind you that Sheen and Kevin Costner aren't the only actors who should have appeared as New Englanders in an Ed Wood production.
            I think the story works because there's enough commitment to historical military fact to make it believable.  The battle scenes probably should have been more visually graphic to evoke the horror of the battle, but the movie makers either didn't have the budget for gore (maybe it was spent on the obviously fake beards) or decided to err on the side of forbearance.  If Gettysburg had been made 8-10 years later, it might have benefited from the newer style of violence-depiction, as in Saving Private Ryan, Thin Red Line, or Gladiator.  It falls a bit short of that, however.
            Finally, it should be noted that the producers/director seem to be operating on a rather simplistic view of the war's historical underpinnings, opting to represent the northern point of view as one united behind the idea of freeing the slaves. Anyone who knows about the Boston busing riots of the 1970s will understand that not all of the north is steeped in racial generosity and brotherhood. Very few who fought on the side of the blue fought because they believed in the abolition of slavery.  They fought to preserve the Union, which is a very different concept.  Abolition of slavery happened to be the issue that forced the South's hand, but it was not the sole cause of the war.  The movie dumbs this down a bit, making the message more like what you'd find in a 5th-grade text book.
            The battle at Gettysburg was certainly pivotal, but viewers should remember that it did not end the Civil War.  The north absolutely needed to win it, but Lee continued to cause the North fits for almost 2 years after Gettysburg.  C. Thomas Howell will continue to cause me fits every time I think of this movie.
            Still and all, the film is very watchable.  And due credit should be given to the re-enactors, arguably the greatest source of credibility for the film
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00064LJVE:"she_is_led_by_love._the_world_moves_for_love._it_kneels_before_it_in_awe.":jim
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00064LJVE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            The Village (Widescreen Edition) (Vista Series): DVD: Jayne Atkinson,Adrien Brody,Frank Collison,Jesse Eisenberg,Brendan Gleeson,Judy Greer,Charlie Hofheimer,Bryce Dallas Howard,William Hurt,Cherry Jones,John Christopher Jones,Fran Kranz,Joaquin Phoenix,Michael Pitt (II),Pascale Renate Smith,Scott Sowers,Zack Wall,Sigourney Weaver,Celia Weston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            "She is led by love. The world moves for love. It kneels before it in awe."
        </title>
        <date>
            November 8, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Jim
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Boston, Ma
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Alright, Im sure you already know what its about, if not, then just read above, because im here, trying to tell you why you should watch it.
            I know, Ill get this out of the way fast. Just watch this movie for what it is, not what you want it to be! People argue that its not scary, or that the twist ending was horrible. Its not a horror movie, its not suposed to scare you. Its a love story. And listen to this: the twist ending?, its not suposed to be a surprise, its suposed form this whole movie, its suposed to define who these characters are, and what they are trying to do. This is a story of love, and of hope and innocence.
            I just dont see how people who are fans of Shyamalans other movies can say "I hated the ending, very predictable" because, fans, you know what Shyamalan does, you know from seeing Signs that hes a deep writer, that he gives much more meaning than what you think its going to be.
            So please, if the only thing thats holding you back from seeing this is the critics, or your friends, then see it anyway. Why would you let other peoples opinions rule what you like, or dont like? Sure, many didnt like it, some didnt even understand it, but that doesnt mean you wont like it. You just have to try it out.
            If you havent had the end ruined for you, thats even better, because you still have this whole movie to look forward to, and if you dont enjoy it, than fine, but atleast you can say yourself that you didnt like it. I know too many people who havent seen it because it got bad reviews.
            If you enjoy a good love story, or even an art-sy type of suspence movie, then im sure you will enjoy it. But its not for everyone. Im sure, if you get bored easily, or if you dont have an imagination (this is a MUST HAVE for any Shyamalan film)
            And then theres the soundtrack, which deserves 5 stars all by itself because its so magical. Shyamalan is one of the few who knows how to use music for film, who can make the music be a character in the movie.
            But before I leave, trust me, dont watch this thinking its a horror movie, because its not. Thats the worst mistake you could make aboiut this film
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00064LJVE:an_interesting,_dramatic_movie_sprinkled_with_suspense:caj
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00064LJVE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            The Village (Widescreen Edition) (Vista Series): DVD: Jayne Atkinson,Adrien Brody,Frank Collison,Jesse Eisenberg,Brendan Gleeson,Judy Greer,Charlie Hofheimer,Bryce Dallas Howard,William Hurt,Cherry Jones,John Christopher Jones,Fran Kranz,Joaquin Phoenix,Michael Pitt (II),Pascale Renate Smith,Scott Sowers,Zack Wall,Sigourney Weaver,Celia Weston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            An interesting, dramatic movie sprinkled with suspense
        </title>
        <date>
            November 8, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            caj
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            I guess the reason I enjoyed the movie so much was because I went into the theatre expecting a good drama. And that's exactly what I got. The story was very interesting to me. I enjoyed the relationships between the villagers, especially Lucious and Ivy.
            The scary moments just added to the drama. Having grown up in the country, I know how scary the woods can be. I loved all the twists to the story.
            The only thing I didn't like was William Hurt's performance. It was too hammy. I think if this critical role had been cast by another actor, the movie would've moved along at a better pace.
            But still a great movie
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00064LJVE:a_utopia_with_dark_edges_and_shadowy_cornerspaces:ellie_reasoner
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00064LJVE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            The Village (Widescreen Edition) (Vista Series): DVD: Jayne Atkinson,Adrien Brody,Frank Collison,Jesse Eisenberg,Brendan Gleeson,Judy Greer,Charlie Hofheimer,Bryce Dallas Howard,William Hurt,Cherry Jones,John Christopher Jones,Fran Kranz,Joaquin Phoenix,Michael Pitt (II),Pascale Renate Smith,Scott Sowers,Zack Wall,Sigourney Weaver,Celia Weston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            A Utopia With Dark Edges And Shadowy Cornerspaces
        </title>
        <date>
            November 8, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Ellie Reasoner
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Cincinnati, Ohio, USA
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            I once thought I was almost alone in liking this creepy and fun 2004 film, but the fact is it seems to be growing on people. It just took a while for those who emerged from theaters declaring The Village a two-hour life support system for a twist ending to appreciate that there's a lot more to this movie than its concluding surprise. (No, I won't give it away, even if by now nearly everyone surely knows what that surprise is, but if you don't know, be careful about reading any farther.) What I grasped about The Village, aside from embracing a story I liked for itself, and for its ending which I didn't see coming, was a message of optimism that said it is possible for people to escape the boundaries and rules of an oppressive time and place, and recreate reality to suit their preferences. Think about that for a minute. People go scatterbrained trying to elude the dictates of our culture today, for instance, with its violence, its corporate intrusions, its governmental omnipresence, and here we saw a successful  experiment in utopian existence set in 1890, and I found that wonderful. I also loved the scenery, the muted color schemes, the attention to period detail and to the agrarian life. The performances of Bryce Dallas Howard, Joachim Phoenix, and William Hurt were also highly underrated. Never has a stretch of bare woods surrounding a meadow looked so foreboding. Never has the monster in the fairy tale been so close at hand. I liked The Village from the first day I saw it, and continue to think well of it even now
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00064LJVE:if_you_like_the_back_of_william_hurt's_head...:therese_bohn
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00064LJVE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            The Village (Widescreen Edition) (Vista Series): DVD: Jayne Atkinson,Adrien Brody,Frank Collison,Jesse Eisenberg,Brendan Gleeson,Judy Greer,Charlie Hofheimer,Bryce Dallas Howard,William Hurt,Cherry Jones,John Christopher Jones,Fran Kranz,Joaquin Phoenix,Michael Pitt (II),Pascale Renate Smith,Scott Sowers,Zack Wall,Sigourney Weaver,Celia Weston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 2
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            1.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            If you like the back of William Hurt's head...
        </title>
        <date>
            November 6, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Therese Bohn
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Endwell, NY United States
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            The only good thing in this movie was Ms. Howard's performance, she is innocent and believable.   I can't understand how good actors like Weaver, Hurt, and Phoenix would let themselves be wasted on this. The 'plain' dialogue among the 'elders' is painfully numbing, choppy, and stilted.  And the directing drove me crazy, especially since M. Night...insists on filming group scenes as is he was just passing through, or following them without ever bothering with close-ups. These scenes make me feel like they were done by an amateur filmmaker with a his first video camera.   If you like the back of William Hurt's head, you'll get plenty of it in this film, the camera seems to avoid his face like the plague; which is too bad, since when he finally has a good speech, we are deprived of the anger I imagine was in his eyes.  I agree with others, I would have worked better as a 30 minute Twilight Zone episode.  Rent it first before you buy, and save some money for a classic thriller, like Psycho
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00064LJVE:total_garbage:krexel
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00064LJVE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            The Village (Widescreen Edition) (Vista Series): DVD: Jayne Atkinson,Adrien Brody,Frank Collison,Jesse Eisenberg,Brendan Gleeson,Judy Greer,Charlie Hofheimer,Bryce Dallas Howard,William Hurt,Cherry Jones,John Christopher Jones,Fran Kranz,Joaquin Phoenix,Michael Pitt (II),Pascale Renate Smith,Scott Sowers,Zack Wall,Sigourney Weaver,Celia Weston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 4
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            1.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Total Garbage
        </title>
        <date>
            November 4, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            krexel
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            California
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            This movie is the most boring, uninteresting piece of garbage I have ever
            wasted my money on. The plot is stupid, the characters are dull and insipid, and the whole movie leaves you asking, as the credits run, "So What?" Don't waste your money!
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00064LJVE:highly_recommended:jamie_ott
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00064LJVE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            The Village (Widescreen Edition) (Vista Series): DVD: Jayne Atkinson,Adrien Brody,Frank Collison,Jesse Eisenberg,Brendan Gleeson,Judy Greer,Charlie Hofheimer,Bryce Dallas Howard,William Hurt,Cherry Jones,John Christopher Jones,Fran Kranz,Joaquin Phoenix,Michael Pitt (II),Pascale Renate Smith,Scott Sowers,Zack Wall,Sigourney Weaver,Celia Weston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 1
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            highly recommended
        </title>
        <date>
            October 30, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Jamie Ott
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Chicago, IL
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            if you are expecting to be scared out of your pants - don't - this movie is not scary but more suspenseful. it is a great movie, with awesome twists and anyone who said that they figured out this movie is a liar. this movie is perfectly written, acted and directed. see this movie
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00064LJVE:not_a_horror,_but_one_of_my_all-time_favorite_shyamalan_films...:m.d._edwards_"avid_aesthete"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00064LJVE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            The Village (Widescreen Edition) (Vista Series): DVD: Jayne Atkinson,Adrien Brody,Frank Collison,Jesse Eisenberg,Brendan Gleeson,Judy Greer,Charlie Hofheimer,Bryce Dallas Howard,William Hurt,Cherry Jones,John Christopher Jones,Fran Kranz,Joaquin Phoenix,Michael Pitt (II),Pascale Renate Smith,Scott Sowers,Zack Wall,Sigourney Weaver,Celia Weston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            2 of 2
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Not a horror, but one of my all-time favorite Shyamalan films...
        </title>
        <date>
            October 24, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            M.D. Edwards "Avid Aesthete"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Newport News, VA
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            It's strange; this just came on FX, and once it was on, I was compelled to stay up and watch the whole thing, even though I've already seen it (in the theatres during its initial release run), and it cost me sleep to watch it all the way through this time around.
            Even for all of the bad press that this movie got, and all of the disgruntled viewers who were expecting another horror, this truly is one of my favorites from M. Night Shyamalan - this, along with "Lady In The Water" (another MUST have for me), is a movie that I feel compelled to add to my collection. As the other reviewers state, it's not truly scary, but more a suspenseful film, as I actually find ALL of Shyamalan's movies to be. In my humble opinion, he's not trying to provide movies best-suited to Halloween scare-fest marathons, but movies that are suspenseful and thought-provoking. As annoying as some of his ticks may be to some viewers, there's thought put into each of his films, unlike stupid wastes of celluloid like "Hostel" and those damned "Saw" movies (enough, already)!
            At least after seeing this in the theatre, I felt that I'd gotten my money's worth for the ticket price, and this is definitely a movie that I feel I could watch repeatedly. In my opinion, the social commentary and romantic aspects only add to the viewing experience provided by this film. Don't buy this if you're looking for a horror like "The Exorcist" - if that's what you want, buy and watch "The Exorcist". If you're looking for a film with twists and turns that tie in to a somewhat deeper meaning, and will have you nodding your head in agreement with the way things play out on screen, buy this movie. Even if you know what happens in the end, I'm sure you'll find yourself wanting to watch it again over time
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00064LJVE:god_awful:jason_ojeda_"beeniebeeniebombom"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00064LJVE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            The Village (Widescreen Edition) (Vista Series): DVD: Jayne Atkinson,Adrien Brody,Frank Collison,Jesse Eisenberg,Brendan Gleeson,Judy Greer,Charlie Hofheimer,Bryce Dallas Howard,William Hurt,Cherry Jones,John Christopher Jones,Fran Kranz,Joaquin Phoenix,Michael Pitt (II),Pascale Renate Smith,Scott Sowers,Zack Wall,Sigourney Weaver,Celia Weston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 8
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            1.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            God Awful
        </title>
        <date>
            October 22, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Jason Ojeda "BeenieBeenieBomBom"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Brewster, New York
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            I knew the ending within the first 10 minutes.  M. Night Shamalamadingdong disappointed me and should go back to his job at Denny's
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:amazing_in_color:r_w_simpson_"tv-holic"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            0 of 1
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Amazing in color
        </title>
        <date>
            November 3, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            R W Simpson "tv-holic"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Melbourne, Australia
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            It was a delight to see this childhood memory again, and in pristine quality with color (if you prefer it in original black &amp; white, turn the color down on your tv set). It brings this 60s series to a whole new generation of fans (my nephews &amp; nieces wouldn't watch it in b&amp;w)
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:coloring_is_terrible!:dr._fritz_juengling
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            3 of 4
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            2.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Coloring is terrible!
        </title>
        <date>
            September 21, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Dr. Fritz Juengling
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Salem, OR United States
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            I'm not reviewing the show itself, but rather the colorization. (If you've seen the show, you know whether you like it; if you haven't seen it, you can read the many other reviews.) The show is lighthearted fun and not to be taken seriously, but if I'm bothered by the colorization, it must be really bad. Unless you like Jeannie with orange hair and people who look like they've drunk a bottle of ink, skip this version and get the BW set.  Then you won't be constantly distracted by weird and wrong colors
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:excellent_first_season.:brian's_reviews
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            3 of 3
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Excellent first season.
        </title>
        <date>
            August 27, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Brian's reviews
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Melbourne Australia
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            There was something special about the first season.
            And this has been colorized,and it realy is great the way they did that.There was a few moments you could tell it was a bit fake,but accross the board it realy has been a great effort to get it looking like this.
            And if you dont like the color version,simply turn off the color on your TV!
            The pilot episode is a personal favorite of mine how it got things started.Especially that bit when she came out of Toney's room with that long shirt!Oh those thigh's!
            Amazingly Barbera Eden got pregnant during this season,and had to wear an extra veil to cover up her pregnancy.
            I have been in love with that woman since i was about 5
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:like_"lighten_up_already_2"_said_in_a_review:j._johnson_"jerry_a_southern_movie_fan_!"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            LIKE "lighten up already 2" said in a review
        </title>
        <date>
            August 21, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            J. JOHNSON "Jerry a southern movie fan !"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Chickamauga, Georgia United States
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Like "lighten up already 2" said in the review of this DVD, I want historical accruacy. I wrote my opinions of the colorized versions of vintage B&amp;W shows in a review of Bewitched the Complete Second Season, which is available in a colorized version. To summarize that review, would an antique dealer ruin a valuable, antique, mahogany, piece of furniture by painting it a bright red ?
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:one_of_my_favorites,_but_wheres_the_info?:robert_bauer
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            0 of 1
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            One of my favorites, but wheres the info?
        </title>
        <date>
            August 10, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Robert Bauer
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Astoria, N.Y. USA
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            This is one of my all time favorite tv shows. Although same in concept and scope than Bewitched, this shows superior cast and performances tower over Bewitched. I believe this show was much more funnier than Bewitched. Barbara Eden stars as Jeannie and Larry Hagman stars as Cap.(later Maj.) Anthony Nelson. And Bill Daily stars as Roger Healy, Maj. Nelsons best friend.  This dvd set covers the entire 1st season (30 episodes) of the series. Since this series 1st season was shot in black and white, this is the preference for me over the alternative colorized dvd set. As far as the video and audio go, the video looks fantastic. Episodes are clean and sharp with no compression. No dirt or scratches noticeable. Audio is in clean 2.0 mono sound. All episodes are complete and uncut. The pilot episode includes a audio commentary with Larry Hagman, Barbara Eden, and Bill Daily. It's nice and pleasant but not very informative. This is the main problem I have about this set. NO INFORMATION!! To me this keeps this set from getting 5 stars. The 4 dvds come in 2 seperate cases covering all 30 episodes. On the back of the cases you get episode #, title of each episode, and small description of each one. I think there should be more info than this, so I had hoped when I played the dvds, got to the main menu, and selected an episode, I would get a small amount of trivia, some more details such as  production date, 1st broadcast date, and cast listing with special guest stars. No such luck. I had hoped for much more info about each episode. You get a 14 minute featurette with new interviews with Sidney Sheldon, Larry Hagmen, Barbara Eden, and Bill Daily, which is a nice (but short) special feature. It's nice to see them together and still very good friends. They were the backbone of this great show (along with the late Hayden Roarke). Hayden Roarke was wonderful as Dr. Alfred Bellows. I would have loved for him to have been there too. In closing this is still a great set to have, and I intend to have all 5 seasons of this great show. I highly recommend the b+w dvd version of this classic show
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:great!_just_superb!!:josephine_miguel
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Great! Just superb!!
        </title>
        <date>
            July 23, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Josephine Miguel
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Hong Kong
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            I love i dream of jeannie, it's just so wholesome and entertaining at the same time. The only thing I wish they've included in the DVD is English subtitles. Sometimes if you've missed what the characters are saying at least you can always check the subtitles. But other than that I'm very glad they've put the series out on DVD.
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:roll_on_season_3......:n._crestani_"natty_nat"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Roll on Season 3......
        </title>
        <date>
            July 23, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            N. Crestani "Natty Nat"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Melbourne, Australia
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            I'm waiting for the release of Season 3 - the best one! This is where Jeannie's evil dark-haired sister shows up for the first time. So silly, so much fun, sweet memories ..
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:i_dream_of_this_dvd_release!:daniel_l._miller_"dannyboy"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 1
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            I Dream Of This DVD Release!
        </title>
        <date>
            July 18, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Daniel L. Miller "Dannyboy"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Toledo, Ohio USA
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Finally, another of my favorite sitcoms is released on DVD!
            I've enjoyed watching re-run after re-run of this "gem" of
            a series for years. For quite awhile the first season was
            not even a part of the syndicated episodes.
            Barbara Eden is fantastic as Jeannie. Poor Tony Nelson
            didn't realize how lucky he really was!
            Larry Hagman played the part of Anthony Nelson with great
            comedic timing. Larry and Barbara together made a fantastic
            team!
            I love the interviews with Barbara, Larry and Bill Daily.
            Even today, the three of them come across as best friends.
            It's no wonder they were so good together in the series!
            I Dream Of Jeannie will always be one of the funniest shows
            ever to grace our TV screens!
            I'm not thrilled about the movie version soon to be released-
            I'll stick with what is best-THE ORIGINAL!
            Now I will wait for one more of my favorite shows-THE PATTY
            DUKE SHOW
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B000E33VZE:i_dream_of_jeannie,_season_one:tammy_helm
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B000E33VZE
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            I Dream of Jeannie - The Complete First Season (Color): DVD: Emmaline Henry,Barton MacLane,Richard Goode,Jerrold Bernstein,Bruce Kessler,Claudio Guzm�n,Leo Garen,Michael Ansara,Russ Mayberry,Theodore J. Flicker,Joseph Goodson,Gene Nelson,Oscar Rudolph,Alan Rafkin,Jon Anderson (III),E.W. Swackhamer,Richard Kinon,Herb Wallerstein
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            1 of 1
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            I Dream of Jeannie, Season one
        </title>
        <date>
            July 10, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Tammy Helm
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Goodyears Bar, California United States
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Wonderful shows/episodes.  My favorite sitcom.  I wish that they played I dream of Jeannie on the television at prime time instead of the junk they have now. You do not have to monitor this program.  It is one that almost any age can enjoy.
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00024I2TA:hidalgo:dbwith_"dbwith"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00024I2TA
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Hidalgo (Full Screen Edition): DVD: Viggo Mortensen,Zuleikha Robinson,Omar Sharif,Louise Lombard,Adam Alexi-Malle,Sa�d Taghmaoui,Silas Carson,Harsh Nayyar,J.K. Simmons,Adoni Maropis,Victor Talmadge,Peter Mensah,Joshua Wolf Coleman,Franky Mwangi,Floyd 'Red Crow' Westerman,Elizabeth Berridge,C. Thomas Howell,Stevan Rimkus,Jerry Hardin,Frank Collison,Joe Johnston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            4.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            HIDALGO
        </title>
        <date>
            November 18, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            dbwith "dbwith"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Nevada
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            As a young White boy growing up on the Navajo reservation was very wonderful, this movie brought back many wonderful memories.  The Navajo friends I had, all rode mustangs so therefore our weekends were spent riding through the bueatiful high deserts of Northern Arizona.  This movie is a great movie, it has all the emotions a person may feel in the 1880's.  Some what, as I felt when we moved to Northern Arizona in 1960.  The people were wonderful to grow up with.  This movie is a great movie, the only problem I had with the DVD is that to see the Bonus Features you have to have a special computer.  I would have been happy to spend the extra money on the movie, if they could have just put it on the DVD.  I would very much like to see the extra parts that have been left out, unless you have a computer that will read these extra parts.  Other wise I would have given this movie a 5 star rating
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00024I2TA:let's_make_this_short_and_sweet...:andrew_olson_"i'm_confused.__wait,_maybe_i'm_not..."
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00024I2TA
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Hidalgo (Full Screen Edition): DVD: Viggo Mortensen,Zuleikha Robinson,Omar Sharif,Louise Lombard,Adam Alexi-Malle,Sa�d Taghmaoui,Silas Carson,Harsh Nayyar,J.K. Simmons,Adoni Maropis,Victor Talmadge,Peter Mensah,Joshua Wolf Coleman,Franky Mwangi,Floyd 'Red Crow' Westerman,Elizabeth Berridge,C. Thomas Howell,Stevan Rimkus,Jerry Hardin,Frank Collison,Joe Johnston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            0 of 1
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            2.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            let's make this short and sweet...
        </title>
        <date>
            October 18, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            Andrew Olson "I'm confused.  Wait, maybe I'm not..."
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            the state of extreme boredom
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            This is one of the most boring movies I have ever seen.  I knew from the very beginning of the movie that there was no way I was going to be able to stay awake through the whole thing.  I was right; I fell asleep about fifteen minutes into it.  Recently, I was offered the chance to watch it again.  I thought, "OK, I didn't see the whole thing, it might have gotten better, so I'll give it another chance." ... Bad mistake.  This little tale about a horse race across a vast desert did nothing to hold my interest for very long.  Hidalgo is the name of the horse.  So what?  That's about as boring as this movie.  So why the 1-star markup? Cause the main character is played by Viggo Mortensen, of Aragorn fame in the smash movie series The Lord of the Rings- and I do like Viggo.  I did not, however, like this movie.  It's kind of fitting it should be set in a desert- cause that's exactly where this movie should be buried, never to bore another wave of audiences again.  If you find yourself overworked and in need of a nice long nap, watch Hidalgo; you'll be out in no time
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00024I2TA:hidalgo:j._j_"justjulia01"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00024I2TA
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Hidalgo (Full Screen Edition): DVD: Viggo Mortensen,Zuleikha Robinson,Omar Sharif,Louise Lombard,Adam Alexi-Malle,Sa�d Taghmaoui,Silas Carson,Harsh Nayyar,J.K. Simmons,Adoni Maropis,Victor Talmadge,Peter Mensah,Joshua Wolf Coleman,Franky Mwangi,Floyd 'Red Crow' Westerman,Elizabeth Berridge,C. Thomas Howell,Stevan Rimkus,Jerry Hardin,Frank Collison,Joe Johnston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            2 of 2
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Hidalgo
        </title>
        <date>
            August 27, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            J. J "justjulia01"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            PA, United States
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Love this movie, caught some of it on TV one week so then did a search on Amazon and brought the movie. Family entertainment Loosly based on the real life Frank T Hopkins who did more to save the wild Mustang than any other
        </review_text>
    </review>
    <review>
        <unique_id>
            B00024I2TA:classic_film_making_on_a_grand_scale.__a_truly_epic_film.:w._n._stape_"nj_review_guy"
        </unique_id>
        <asin>
            B00024I2TA
        </asin>
        <product_name>
            Hidalgo (Full Screen Edition): DVD: Viggo Mortensen,Zuleikha Robinson,Omar Sharif,Louise Lombard,Adam Alexi-Malle,Sa�d Taghmaoui,Silas Carson,Harsh Nayyar,J.K. Simmons,Adoni Maropis,Victor Talmadge,Peter Mensah,Joshua Wolf Coleman,Franky Mwangi,Floyd 'Red Crow' Westerman,Elizabeth Berridge,C. Thomas Howell,Stevan Rimkus,Jerry Hardin,Frank Collison,Joe Johnston
        </product_name>
        <product_type>
            dvd
        </product_type>
        <helpful>
            8 of 8
        </helpful>
        <rating>
            5.0
        </rating>
        <title>
            Classic film making on a grand scale.  A truly epic film.
        </title>
        <date>
            August 13, 2006
        </date>
        <reviewer>
            W. N. Stape "NJ Review Guy"
        </reviewer>
        <reviewer_location>
            Bayonne, NJ USA
        </reviewer_location>
        <review_text>
            Hidalgo is based upon a true story, so it's no wonder it's thrilling, truth being stranger than fiction and all.  Although it's highly doubtful that everything in the movie actually happened, Frank Hopkins was indeed a real life cowboy, master horseman and rider and he did participate in the great Bedouin horse race of the Middle East known as the "Ocean of Fire" in the 1890's.
            This wonderfully stylized and lovingly crafted film clocks in at over two hours, yet never bores and your interest should never waver.  The international cast is terrific, led by Viggo Mortensen in a low-key, subtle performance which brings depth and a real sense of nobility to the notion of a "cowboy'.  We've seen loads of silver screen gun slingers, bandits and marshals from icons like the swaggering John Wayne to the laconic Clint Eastwood, but with Viggo's Frank Hopkins, we may now be witness to one of the most balanced and interesting portrayals of an authentic cowpoke.  And it's all the more interesting because Frank Hopkins isn't all cowboy - half of him is Native American.  This internal duality and cultural division brings character shadings and a unique sense of perspective to Hopkins.
            Balancing the tensions of Native Americans with the US Government of the time, the film explores Frank Hopkin's journey between two worlds - that of a half Native American with loyal ties to his tribe and his jobs as a pony express rider and performer in Wild Bill Hickcock's show, all while having to live in the White Man's world.  When he's invited to participate in the Bedouin Race, Frank soon discovers there's a whole other world out there bound by similar dogmatic traditions, where women must hide their faces behind veils, much like he's chosen to hide his native ancestry to enable him to live an easier life.
            Sweeping cinematography beautifully composes authentic locations and the stunt choreography infuses the race and the action set-ups with fun and authenticity.  Viggo must have definitely "lived" horses for the film, irregardless of his prior expertise with them.  He clearly is at the reigns of the horse most of the time and he's totally capable and always convincing.  Hidalgo the horse may qualify for his own sequel or a TV series.  This beautiful animal is more expressive than many human actors and it's just one of the many joys and reasons to give this film a chance.  Apparently lost by audiences in it's initial theatrical release, Hidalgo should be discovered by every movie lover.
        </review_text>
    </review>
</annotation>
